Guide to the Frederick Elisha Shapleigh papers, 1908-1920.
Shapleigh, Frederick Elisha papers, 1908-1920.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Frederick Elisha Shapleigh papers, 1908-1920.
2454
Frederick Elisha Shapleigh, 1884-1968.
3 cubic ft.
Papers, correspondence, reports, sociological surveys, manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of Frederick Elisha Shapleigh concerning his work in rural sociology and education.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers of Frederick Elisha Shapleigh concerning his work in rural sociology and education (1908-1914), including correspondence, reports, sociological surveys, and several of his manuscripts on the subjects; also papers relating to his work for the Public Education Association in Buffalo (1914-1920), including correspondence, statistical studies, a complete file of "School and Community" which he edited, and clippings.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Shapleigh, Frederick Elisha,1884-1968.; Public Education Association.
Subjects:
Education--New York (State)--Buffalo.; Sociology, Rural.; Education, Rural.; Educators.; Sociologists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, Oct. 15, 1908-Nov. 22, 1912 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, Dec. 5, 1913-Apr. 8, 1915 (Box 1)
- Preliminary Survey of Montgomery County, Maryland, 1911 (Box 1)
- Millbrook Survey; Letters, Survey Blanks, Methods of Use, Milk and Water Tests, May 23, 1912-May 23, 1913 (Box 1)
- Correspondence and Original Survey Blanks for the Morris County Survey; Inc. corres. Henry Israel, Albert E. Roberts, YMCA (see also Box 4), Jan. 3, 1913-Mar. 10, 1914 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Articles and Projected Monographs on Rural Surveys, 1912-1913 (Box 1)
- Plans for Rural Betterment of Cattaraugus County and Letters of Endorsement for the Plan (see also Box 3), 1913 (Box 1)
- Correspondence Dealing with Cattaraugus County and Erie County Surveys (see also Box 3), July 9, 1913-Feb. 5, 1914 (Box 1)
- Five Articles on "The Social Survey," Published in the Epworth Herald, Chicago, 1914 (Box 1)
- Rural Social Survey Bibliographies - incl. FES's, George F. Wells', etc. (Box 1)
- Clippings and Publicity for Talbot County, Maryland - broadsides, pamphlets, etc. (Box 1)
- Talbot County, Maryland. Final survey with intro., 61 pp., maps, charts, 1911 (Box 2)
- Preliminary Write-up of Survey of Talbot County, Maryland, 31 pcs. unbound, 1911 (Box 2)
- Hardback bound text: American Rural Communities, 196 pp. typescript, 1909 (Box 2)
- Hardback bound text: The Millbrook Survey, 239 pp. typescript, carbon; illus., charts, maps. "Undertaken with the Cooperation of the County Works Departments of the Dutchess County and New York State Committees of the YMCA", 1913 (Box 2)
- A Preliminary Statement concerning the Survey of Cattaraugus County, ts.cc. Presented to the Buffalo Presbytery, Sept. 1913 (Box 3)
- Community Surveys in Cattaraugus County; Folder #1, ts. carbon. Illus., 1913 (Box 3)
- Community Surveys in Cattaraugus County; Folder #2, ts. carbon. Illus., 1913 (Box 3)
- The Social Survey in Cattaraugus County, A Brief Statement Concerning Its Findings. Presented to the Olean Ministers' Association. 26 pp. ts. carbon, Nov. 1913 (Box 3)
- A Rural Survey in Cattaraugus County, 77 pp. ts. carbon; charts, illus.; also MSS. draft, Dec. 1913 (Box 3)
- Community Surveys in Erie County. Akron, Glenwood, Griffins Mills. ts. cc. illus., 1913 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, Buffalo Public Schools (see Boxes 5-8), Mar. 5, 1914-Oct. 29, 1917 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, Buffalo Public Schools (see Boxes 5-8), Nov. 23, 1917-Jan. 30, 1919 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, Buffalo Public Schools (see Boxes 5-8), Feb. 5, 1919-Oct. 25, 1920 (Box 3)
- Original Handwritten Manuscript of A Reconnaisance Social Survey of Morris County, New Jersy, 111 pp., 1913 (Box 4)
- A Reconnaissance Social Survey, Morris County, New Jersey, 1913. ts. carbon (Box 4)
- Dissertation for Cornell University, The Rural Social Survey: Its Purposes and Its Methods. 362 pp. typescript with illus., charts. (bound with string), 1913 (Box 4)
- Beginnings, Plans, Membership Lists, and Trustees Meetings of the Public Education Association, 1914-1920 (Box 5)
- Publicity Plans of Public Education Association, 1914-1918 (Box 5)
- Financial Reports of the Public Education Association; Plans of the Public Education Association, 1914-1920 (Box 5)
- Activities of the Research Bureau of the Public Education Association of Buffalo, 1914-1920 (Box 5)
- Citizen Cooperation in Educational Research, Feb. 1919 (Box 5)
- The Intellectual Ability of Public School Children Intelligence Tests, 1919 (Box 5)
- Material for a Directory of Organizations of Buffalo, Sept. 1919 (Box 5)
- Public Education Association Office Organization (Box 5)
- Organizations Cooperating with the Public Education Association of Buffalo (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous Updated Manuscripts, Folder #1 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous Undated Manuscripts, Folder #2 (Box 5)
- Undated Miscellaneous Material (Box 5)
- Printed Matter - Editorials from School and Community and Miscellaneous Material Dealing with the Public Education Association (Box 5)
- School Janitors: Appointment, Title, Liscense, Assistants, Responsibilities, Relationships, June 1915 (Box 6)
- The Organization and Function of a Board of Education, 1915 (Box 6)
- Quotations from letters regarding charts on Public School Administration, 1915 (Box 6)
- Relation of the State to the City School Systems, 1915 (Box 6)
- The Relation of the State to the City School System - partial text, 1915 (Box 6)
- Chart on Administration, Mar. 1916 (Box 6)
- Outline for Study of Salaries, June 1916 (Box 6)
- Legal Foundation of the Buffalo Public Schools, Aug. 1916 (Box 6)
- Methods of Establishing Boards of Education in 57 School Districts, Aug. 1916 (Box 6)
- Methods of Selecting and Standardizing High School Texts, Dec. 1916 (Box 6)
- Analysis of Age and Progress Statistics in Grade 7B, Dec. 1916 (Box 6)
- Appointment of Teachers in Selected Cities, Dec. 1916 (Box 6)
- Status of Superintendent of Education, 1916 (Box 6)
- Heating and Ventilation in Buffalo Schools, Jan. 1917 (Box 6)
- Employment and Compensation of Superintendents, Teachers and Other Employees of Appointed Boards of Education, Feb. 1917 (Box 6)
- Salaries of Administrative Heads of School Systems, Clerks, Secretaries, Stenographers, Assistants, etc., Mar. 1917 (Box 6)
- Age-Grade Progress Chart for 5A and 7B in the Buffalo Schools, Apr. 1917 (Box 6)
- Schools vs. War-time Efficiency, Sept. 1917 (Box 6)
- Brief Reports on School Centers, 1917 (Box 6)
  "The Citizen and His Job"
  Expenditures, Per Capita, for Schools
  Expenditures by the U.S. Government for Various Purposes, 1914-1917
  Suggested Requirement for New School Buildings
- Educational Code of New York, 1917 (Box 6)
- Ages and Progress of Children in the Public Schools of Buffalo, Feb. 1918 (Box 6)
- War-time Industrial Training in the Public Schools of Large Cities, Apr. 1918 (Box 6)
- Vocational Courses Offered in Buffalo High School and Vocational High Schools, Oct. 1918 (Box 6)
- A Bibliography of Educational Research, May 1918 (Box 6)
- Two Bulletins of the National Association of Directors of Educational Research, 1918 (Box 6)
- Educational Opportunities for Dull Boys and Girls, July 1918 (Box 6)
- The National Emergency in Education, Dec. 1918 (Box 6)
- Junior Red Cross Membership and Activities during World War I, 1918 (Box 6)
- Conference Committee on Education, 1918 (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous, 1918 (Box 6)
- Minutes of Meetings for School and Community Establishment. Early Drafts, Dummies, First Copies of Publication, 1919 (Box 7)
- The Teaching Learning Process in Symbols by Frederick P. Woellner, 1919 (Box 7)
- Handwritten Editorials for School and Community, 1919-1920 (Box 7)
- School and Community, Complete File, Dec. 4, 1919-Aug. 20, 1920 (Box 7)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1914-1920 (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous (Box 7)
- Articles clipped from The School Board Journal, 1915-1919 (Box 8)
  Home Rule and the State Regulation of City School Systems, Aug. 1915
  Commission Government and the Administration of City School Systems, Nov. 1915
  School Administration in Non-Commission Government Cities, Dec. 1915
  The Legal Foundation of the Buffalo School System, Aug. 1916
  The Compensation of School Janitors, Dec. 1916
  Examinations, Eligible Lists and Appointemnts of Teachers, Mar. 1917
  New York's Revised Educational Code, June 1917
  Educational Research Versus War-time Efficiency, July 1917
  College, Experience and Character Versus the Selection of Teachers, Oct. 1917
  Citizen Co-operation in Educational Research, June 1919
- A softback copy of a publication by the Research Bureau, Public Education Association of Buffalo, concerning A Study of the Salary Schedules of City School Systems, Sept. 1916 (Box 8)